<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2020 University of Amsterdam -->
<component type="desktop">
	<id>org.jaspstats.JASP</id>
	<launchable type="desktop-id">org.jaspstats.JASP.desktop</launchable>
	<name>JASP</name>
	<summary>Classical and Bayesian Statistics</summary>
	<metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
	<project_license>AGPL-3.0+</project_license>
	<content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
	<developer_name>University of Amsterdam</developer_name>
    <update_contact>joris@jorisgoosen.nl</update_contact>
	<description>
		<p>
			​JASP is a cross platform statistical software program with a state-of-the-art graphical user interface. 
			It offers standard analysis procedures in both	their classical and Bayesian form. 
		</p>
		<p>
			It was designed with the user in mind: APA-formatted tables can be copy-pasted in your word processor, output can be extensively annotated, adjustment of input options dynamically changes the output, and selecting 
			old output revives the associated input choices for inspection and adjustment.
		</p>
		<p>
			JASP is also statistically inclusive, as it offers both frequentist and Bayesian analysis methods. 
			Indeed, the primary motivation for JASP is to make it easier for statistical practitioners to conduct Bayesian analyses.
		</p>
	</description>
	<screenshots>
		<screenshot type="default">
			<caption xml:lang="en-GB">Shows JASP Descriptives</caption>
			<image type="source" width="965" height="685">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jasp-stats/jasp-desktop/development/Tools/flatpak/flatpak_screenshot_0_small.png</image>
		</screenshot>
	</screenshots>
	<url type="homepage">http://www.jasp-stats.org</url>
	<url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues</url>
	<url type="donation">https://jasp-stats.org/donate/</url>
  <branding>
  <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#14a1e3</color>
  <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#14a1e3</color>
  </branding>
	<releases>
	<release version="0.19.2" date="2024-10-21">
                <description>
Beta
                </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.19.1" date="2024-09-10">
          <description>
0.19.1 (September 10th 2024)
    Bug Fixes:
        Filter being ignored in Levels constraint checks (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2853)
          </description>
        </release>
            <release version="0.19.0" date="2024-07-15">
                <description>
0.19.0 (July 15th 2024)

    New analyses:
        Raincloud Plots
        Bayesian process analysis
    Data Type check improvements
        Indicator and tooltip for type conversion
        Min and max levels constraints for variables
        When allowed, possibility to change type inside the analysis
    Data Editing:
        Redesign the Label Editor
        Possibility to recode value
        Automatic reorder labels per value
        Real values in grey when differ from labels
    New language: Italian
    Improve welcome page with reference to bug/feature reports
    Import Data
        Better handling of ODS file (352, 2660)
        Read missing values from sav/readstat (2500)
    Improve Latex editor (5413)
    Table title gets APA styles (5345)
    Modules fixed and new features
        Descriptives
            Improve Shapiro-Wilk test (1209)
            Added bound of Percentiles (155)
        ANOVA:
            Use multivariate as default for follow-up tests RM ANOVA (1221, 1642)
            Letter based posthoc grouping + dunn relocating + allow singular model (321)
            Contrast-specific error term for planned contrats in the context of RM-ANOVA (1642)
            Request for Letter-Based Representation of All-Pairwise Comparisons in post-hoc testing (342)
            Incorrect CI bars for repeated measures ANOVA (standard and Bayesian) (1187)
            Effect size for Kruskall Wallis and Dunns test (post hoc) (1905)
            CI error bars on rm-ANOVA much too small - can the Morey's correction be optional? (1227)
            RM ANOVA - allow interactions between within/between factors in marginal means (2351)
            Dunn's post hoc non functional (2678)
            Option to only compute and display relevant post-hocs (637)
            Presenting the results in post hoc tests for n-factorial ANOVA fixing one of the factors and showing the statistical difference among the levels of the other factor (2696)
            Error in JASP homogeneity test for repeated measures ANOVA (2711)
            Can't plot interactions for BANOVAs and RM BANOVAs (2573)
        T-Tests
            Niggling plot differences between classical and Bayesian paired t-test (573)
            Confidence intervals for Wilcoxon signed-rank test are reported even when requested confidence level is not achievable (2037)
            The abbreviated Mann-Whitney statistics (1735)
            Bayesian Paired-Samples t-test (Wilcoxon) - Won't run with ordinal data, but will with scale data (2102)
        Mixed Models
            Change comparison group for mixed-models to fit other analyses types (1970)
            MixedModelsLMM with only ~1 in fixed part (2092)
            Allow Mixed models to only estimate the random effects (2780
        Process:
            Bootstrap percentile intervals (2657)
            Fix short variable name (2635)
            Add covariances between mediators and mediator-interaction terms (86)
            Model fail with Hayes configuaration (2650)
            Bayesian Process Model- estimate failed with lavaan things (2628)
            Does not perform local tests (2622)
            Multiple mediated processes become one (2473
            Renaming model erases input (2469)
        Regression
            Classical Linear Regression: cannot add ordinal variable (2243)
            Change Bayes factor label according to the hypothesis value (286)
            Error when interaction term is entered in regression (1679)
            Reintroduce stepwise/forward/backward regression with factors (2597)
            Block Function for Hierarchical Linear Regression (176)
            Additional statistics for the regression module (1637)
            Hierarchical logistic regression (entering predictors in blocks (1675)
            Error when running moderator analysis (2727)
            linear weighing in Cohen kappa (2175)
        Reliability
            Output factor loadings when computing frequentist McDonald's omega (2525)
        Factor
            Export/Save function for factor scores in EFA and PCA (101)
            CFA error with grouping variable (2182)
            Unidimensional omega of Relibability/Unidimensional Reliability differs from that of Factor/CFA (2655)
        JAGS
            Error in binamy classification (2537)
        AUDIT:
            Separate the prior most likely misstatement and the expected misstatements in the sample (459)
        Machine Learning:
            Transpose confusion matrix, Show training and data validation split options for decision trees, support vector machines, better help (318)
            ROC for Naive Bayes Classification does not work (2794)
            error while setting test set indicator for Boosting classification (1838)
            Machine Learning Regression: add scaled MSE in the evaluation metrics (2619)
            Incorrect test accuracy for decision tree classifier when one class doesn't contain any prediction (2596)
        SEM
            No negative correlation in Partial Least Squared SEM (2086)
            Error message when trying to perform LGCM (2764)
            SEM module mislabels models (2690
            Latent Growth modeling get error (2510)
            Equality Constraints in Multigroup SEM have at least 2 bugs (2225)
            listwise deletion in PCA (2419)
            Adding estimation of indirect and total effects to SEM module (1980)
        Visual Modeling
            Error in module Visual Modeling / Mixed Modeling (2216)
            Flexplot with categorial variables shows absolute Differences now (2423)
            only allow 2 variables in the input boxes (2750)
        Equivalence T-Tests
            Repair Independent Samples T-Test(1940)
        Learn Bayes
            Binary Classification: fails to accept continuous and binary discrete variables (2531)
        Distribution
            F-Distribution error (2640)
        Quality Control
            Control charts adjustable control limits and targets (1790)
            Add specification limits to x-mR chart in process capability study (2443)
            nested gauge r and R results differ to other software (2048)
            Name of the Catagorical variables are being pulled from wrong table (2392)
            Capability Study: Cannot deal with large values (2440)
            out-of-control signals (2318)
            Error in tableRListCombined[['test3']]: subscript out of bounds (2674)


                </description>
        </release>
          <release version="0.18.3" date="2024-01-10">
                <description>
Bug fixes:
	• Some older JASP files did not open correctly in 0.18.2 (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2517)
  • Filter errors and improve clarity (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2515)
  • Incorrect handling of decimal separators in CSVs (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2518)
  • Audit Sampling workflow getting stuck (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2503)
  • Problem with Windows Zip version (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2502)
  • Update flexplot (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2494)
                </description>
        </release>
		<release version="0.18.2" date="2024-01-02">
            <description>
**New Features and Improvements**

- New module:
  - Survival (Beta)
  - Process (Beta)

- Data Editing:
  - Redesign the Variable setting window
  - Possibility to switch computed columns to not computed and vice-versa
  - Add empty values settings per variable
  - Make JASP readable on small screen
  - Copy/Paste with headers work between JASP and other spreadsheet editor.
  - Undo/Redo shortcut available everywhere on data editing mode

- Results:
  - Add video support in annotation (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-desktop/pull/5293)

- Windows Installation
  - Add MSIX Installation in [Windows Store](https://apps.microsoft.com/detail/9P08CWG12JNL).

- Audit:
  - implements algorithm auditing (i.e., model fairness, a new section in the module): https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspAudit/pull/371

- Factor/CFA
  - Option to fix intercepts to zero in mean structure (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2223)
  - Add structural invariance and mean structure identification options (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2378, https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspFactor/pull/193)

- Machine Learning:
  - Add Naive Bayes classification analysis (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspMachineLearning/pull/244):
Implements some explainable modelling ('XAI') features from the DALEX package
    - After model performance, implemented an option in all supervised analyses to show feature importance metrics (via https://ema.drwhy.ai/featureImportance.html).
    - After feature importance, implemented an option in all supervised analyses (and the prediction analysis) to explain the predictions of the model as a sum of feature contributions (via https://ema.drwhy.ai/breakDown.html#breakDown).
    - Added multivariate normality check in the LDA analysis (https://github.com/jasp-statsjasp-issues#2272)
    - Adds a bare-bones linear regression analysis as a baseline method in which the user can use a training and test set to compare the results with other techniques.
  - Linear Regression: Add an option to display the regression equation for (regularised) linear regression (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspMachineLearning/pull/227)
  - Optimization for support vector machines and decision trees (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspMachineLearning/issues/84)

- SEM:
  - Add mean structure option fixing mean intercepts to zero (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspSem/pull/186)


**Bug fixes**
- Multiple labelfilters do not combine correctly (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2376)
- Filter still active after reopen new session (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2344)
- Export csv file from .jasp file will lose values (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2396)
- Latex in darkmode (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-desktop/pull/5311)
- Bayesian ANOVA: Fix Single model inference (https://github.com/jasp-stats/INTERNAL-jasp/issues/2426)
- Learn Bayes: fix bracket at logBF10 (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspLearnBayes/pull/171)
- Machine Learning:
  - Do not scale the target variable in regression anymore.
  - Fix bugs in Neural Network analyses related to activation function use (had wrong input for linear.output argument).
- Quality Control
  - Graph variation components has not been built (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2273)
  - Percentage Process Variation Graph hadn't been built (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2274)
  - Attributes Agreement Analysis analysis crash (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2286)
  - Added help files (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspQualityControl/pull/285)
  - Fixed issue that sometimes broke the RSM analysis (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspQualityControl/pull/281). The rsm package calculated some "canonicals" that were not used in the JASP output. Setting the threshold to calcuate these to 0 resolved the issue.
  - Removed option to specify blocks again, breaks too often.
  - Removed options to specify manual terms for RSM analysis, breaks often and is not really useful without possibility of adding squared terms.
- Regression analyses:
  - Bug in German translation (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspRegression/issues/268, https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2405)
  - Wrong values of Nagelkerke and Cox and Snell R^2 reported (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2368)
- Reliability
  - CI for Krippendorff's alpha (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2318)
- SEM
  - Chi-square change with addtion of second model (https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2302)
            </description>
        </release>
	    <release version="0.18.1" date="2023-09-26">
                <description>
**New Features and Improvements**

*   New module: Learn Stats

**Bug fixes**

*   Data Editing:
    *   Beter undo/redo shortcut handling ([#5262](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-desktop/pull/5262))
    *   Add copy/cut/paste with header ([#5249](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-desktop/pull/5249))
    *   Make remove columns/rows quicker([#5242](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-desktop/pull/5242))
*   Descriptives:
    *   Incorrect confidence interval in descriptive statistics ([#2288](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2288))
    *   Likert plot long data ([#2251](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2251))
    *   Use ColorPalette ([#216](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspDescriptives/pull/216))
*   LearnBayes: Use ColorPalette ([#167](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspLearnBayes/pull/167))
*   SEM:
    *   Use ColorPalette ([#177](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspSem/pull/177))
    *   fix disattenuation bug and handle resampling options better ([#2260](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2260))
    *   Merged notes additional fit measures ([#147](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspSem/pull/147))
*   Meta Analysis, hot fixes for RoBMA ([#196](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspMetaAnalysis/pull/196) and [#197](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspMetaAnalysis/pull/197)):
    *   fix output ordering
    *   fix diagnostics plots
    *   fix effect size output option
    *   fix 'plotsIndividualModelsOrder'
    *   plot prior distributions under custom models
    *   incorrectly disabled prior scale menu on custom
*   Predictive Analytics: [#11](https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspPredictiveAnalytics/pull/11)
                </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.18.0" date="2023-08-31">
                <description>
Main New Feature:
	• Data Editing
New Features and Improvements:
	• New module: Robust TTests
	• Show color palettes https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2122
	• Make LaTeX formula editable: https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-desktop/pull/5186
Bug fixes:
	• ANOVA: Refreshing old jasp file engine crash https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-test-release/issues/2347
	• T-Test: cannot render Bayesian sequential analysis with robustness check https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2252
	• CFA error with grouping variable: https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/2182
	• Improve Quality Control: https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspQualityControl/pull/263
	• Fix variance components plot failing for i18n: https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspQualityControl/pull/270
	• Add more translatable strings: https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-desktop/pull/5144
	• Application stops responding when filtering data: https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues/1644
	• JASP files can be send via E-Mails, there are not blocked by E-Mail servers.
	• Learn Bayes: Buffons Needle problems when tosses = 0: https://github.com/jasp-stats/jaspLearnBayes/pull/169
                </description>
        </release>
	</releases>
​</component>
