<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2020 University of Amsterdam -->
<component type="desktop">
	<id>org.jaspstats.JASP</id>
	<launchable type="desktop-id">org.jaspstats.JASP.desktop</launchable>
	<name>JASP</name>
	<summary>Standard statistical analyses, both classical and Bayesian</summary>
	<metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
	<project_license>AGPL-3.0+</project_license>
	<content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
	<developer_name>University of Amsterdam</developer_name>
    <update_contact>joris@jorisgoosen.nl</update_contact>
	<description>
		<p>
			​JASP is a cross platform statistical software program with a state-of-the-art graphical user interface. 
			It offers standard analysis procedures in both	their classical and Bayesian form. 
		</p>
		<p>
			It was designed with the user in mind: APA-formatted tables can be copy-pasted in your word processor, output can be extensively annotated, adjustment of input options dynamically changes the output, and selecting 
			old output revives the associated input choices for inspection and adjustment.
		</p>
		<p>
			JASP is also statistically inclusive, as it offers both frequentist and Bayesian analysis methods. 
			Indeed, the primary motivation for JASP is to make it easier for statistical practitioners to conduct Bayesian analyses.
		</p>
	</description>
	<translation/>
	<screenshots>
		<screenshot type="default">
			<caption xml:lang="en-GB">Shows the dataviewer of JASP flanked with the options and output for the Independent Samples T-Test</caption>
			<image type="source" width="1600" height="900">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jasp-stats/jasp-desktop/development/Tools/flatpak/JASP-screenshot-0.png</image>
		</screenshot>
	</screenshots>
	<url type="homepage">http://www.jasp-stats.org</url>
	<url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues</url>
	<url type="donation">https://jasp-stats.org/donate/</url>
	<releases>
	<release version="0.16.0" date="2021-11-08">
			<description>
				New release 0.16

				New Features:

				- Meta analysis:
				-- WAAP-WLS and PET-PEESE
				-- Predictive Performance
    			- Cochrane Meta-Analyses
    			- Summary statistics - General Bayesian Tests
				- Machine learning:
				-- Neural Networks
				-- Model Saving
				-- Prediction
				- Audit has a revamped UI
				- ANOVA now includes GORICA
				- Descriptives now has tile plots
				- Circular Statistics are added
				- Regression now has proportions in confusion matrix and adds marginal effect plots
			</description>
	</release>
	<releases>
		<release version="0.15.0" date="2021-09-21">
					<description>
						New release 0.15

						New features and improvements

						- Plot editing
						-- Allow custom fonts in plots
						-- Resized plots are kept after refreshing 
						- Supports more languages, English, German, Dutch, Galician, Japanese, Portuguese and rudimentary Chinese and Spanish
						- Windows workarounds:
						-- Support reading "native" locale encoded csvs and utf-8 both, dependent on BOM. (Aka save as csv vs csv with utf-8 in excel)
						-- Support installing jasp for user with username in native locale characters
						- New module “Prophet” for time series prediction
						- Descriptives: 
						-- Dot plots
						-- Stem-and-leaf tables
						-- Descriptives table can now be transposed
						- SEM: 
						-- Possibility to define several models
						-- MIMIC model analysis
						-- Latent Growth analysis
						-- Improved labels in tables
						-- Footnote fit-table listwise deletion
						- T-Tests and ANOVAs: Raincloud plots
						- Distributions: Major update including 23 new continuous and 5 discrete distributions
						- Learn Bayes:
						-- Binary classification
						-- Game of chance
						-- Game of skill
						-- Buffon’s needle
						-- Some edge case scenario and esthetical fixes for binomial estimation
						- Regression:
						-- Bootstrapping in correlation
						-- Categorical variables can be used as predictors in linear regression
						-- Adjusted lower limit for wls weights 
						-- Relaxed error check on the covariance matrix of predictors 
						- Frequencies:
						- Show more informative footnote when phi cannot be calculated
						-- Choose odds ratio for contingency table
						-- Guttman and Kruskal’s lambda for contingency tables
						- Factor analysis: Factor loadings can now be sorted in EFA and CFA
						- Mixed Models
						-- Fixing plotting themes
						-- Improving warning messages
						-- Changing default links for gamma and negative binomial family
						- Meta-Analyses - Complete update of the RoBMA module
						- Reliability
						-- Classical intraclass correlation coefficients 
						-- Adding options for mean and SD
						-- Restructuring of R-code to improve computational time and reduce error-proneness
						-- Manage huge .jasp file sizes produced by sampling in reliability analysis
						- Audit - Added mean and median to descriptive output of prior and posterior distribution

					Bug fixes
						- Several fixes to sav loading (spss files)
						- Loading data repeated measures ANOVA
						- Cohen’s d was incorrectly calculated
						- Fixed error in density graph Bayesian meta-analysis
						- Fixed error in computing the total number of edges in Network analysis
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.14.1" date="2020-10-14">
					<description>
						New release 0.14

						New features and improvements 
							- Adjusting for publication bias in meta-analysis
							- Robust Bayesian meta-analysis
							- Selection models
							- Learn Bayes module
							- PDF export of results
							- Choose your font
							- German translation
							- Frequentist partial correlations
							- Confidence and prediction intervals in linear regression
							- New distributions in the Distributions module (log-normal and logistic)

						Bug fixes 
							- Large dataset: Crash when changing variable type #938
							- Jasp cannot be installed without admin privileges #861
							- Mangled name in 0.13 #851
							- Analysis of Effects: Across Matched Models #852
							- Corrections of bugs found during the workshop #4257
							- Summary Statistics Bayesian Independent Samples T-Test: Labels in prior and posterior plots switch upon changing from BF10 to BF01, while they shouldn't #796
							- Quill: Add the ability to change line width, as in docs via paragraph (singel, double spacing, etc) #694
							- Quill: Ghost text? #695
							- Quill: Tooltip for Quill #696
							- Issues with display of icons and characters #929
							- ROC and PR curve (after classification) #277
							- Plots on linux are only saved as png #889
							- Labels not being displayed anymore in spreadsheet #933
							- Minor display glitch in spreadsheet #935
							- Major inconsistency between frequentist and bayesian non parametric paired t-test #868
							- Add methods median, ward.d, ward.d2 and mcquitty #4222
							- Column order option does not work #914
							- Contingency tables properly reverse column labels #4211
							- Save image as SVG #873
							- Selecting a custom spreadsheet editor not working #901
							- Further Customization of Plots #279
							- Posterior summaries in Bayesian linear regression and Bayesian ANOVAs now show exclusion probabilities #625
							- Log Odds Ratio value not updated #915
							- Bayesian Mixed Effect Models with aggregated binomial family #957 
							- Reliability: Average interitem correlation 95%CI, do not include point estimate! #888
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.13.1" date="2020-07-13">
					<description>
						Bug fixing release for 0.13

						Fixes:
							- Make sure analyses actually work on (windows) systems where the user has non-ascii characters in their name
							- PPTX not save saved on signed mac
							- Fixed a bug with changing column type
							- Stabilised the macOS intel iris GPU bug (upgrade to Qt 5.15)
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.13.0" date="2020-07-01">
						<description>
							New Features and improvements: 
							- Engine improvements 

							New modules and analyses: 
							- Generalized Linear Mixed Models (both Bayesian and classical)
							- Reliability module (both Bayesian and classical) 
							- R-console (beta) 

							Analyses improvements 
							- SEM module: Allow ordinal variables in CFA 
							- Network analysis module: Added expected influence 'centrality' (jasp-issue #411)
							- Saving plots as powerpoint files

							Bug fixes: 
							- P value shown as 0.00 instead of &lt;.001 (jasp-issue #706)
							- JASP "quits unexpectedly" after opening a file and then quitting by closing the menu (jasp-issue #667)
							- Pixelated user interface with JASP 0.12.2.0 (jasp-issue #720)
							- Issue with Informed Prior for Bayesian Independent Samples T-Test (jasp-issue #730)
							- Bug on Bayesian Repeated Measures ANOVA (jasp-issues #737 #774)
							- JASP has difficulty handling extended missing value codes in Stata (jasp-issue #733) 
							- Audit selection analysis (jasp-issue #699)
							- Variable type not updated in Post Hoc Tests (jasp-issue #708) 
							- Error in an independent sample T-test (jasp-issue #724) 
							- JASP crashes on exit (jasp-issue #777)
							- Very slow estimation of correlation matrix (jasp-issues #679 #712)
							- Tjur R^2 wrongly calculated (jasp-issue #764)
							- App does not display correctly (jasp-issue #775) 
							- Mixed Modeling (Visual Modeling [BETA]) (jasp-issue #763)
							- Network analysis: SPELLING MISTAKE (jasp-issue #751) 
							- Network analysis - Changing Legend does not change the Centrality Plot (jasp-issue #702)
							- Paired T-tests - Changing the hypothesis provides a more informative footnote (jasp-issue#758)
				</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.12.2" date="2020-04-22">
			<description>
				- Fix a bug where ANOVA RM would crash if there were columns named with certain single letters
				- Some more smaller points
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.12.1" date="2020-04-15">
			<description>
				Small fix for 0.12.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.12" date="2020-04-10">
			<description>
				Updated R to 3.6.1 and rewrote (almost) all analyses to make use of new internal API (jaspResults).
				Added a dark theme and support for dutch language.
				Modules added: Bayesian meta-analysis, JAGS, Discover Distributions, Visual Modeling and Equivalence Testing.
				And much more, see our blog for more information!
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.11.1" date="2019-10-11">
			<description>
				This version fixes a bug with certain systems having trouble running certain analyses when the path contains non-latin characters.
				It also removes the inherit-gl-extension which causes some trouble for certain flatpak users.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.11.0" date="2019-09-24">
			<description>
				This version adds the Machine Learning Module, which adds a variety of classification, regression and clustering analyses.
				It also adds support for reading Stata and SAS files while updating the SPSS support through the use of ReadStat.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.10.2" date="2019-07-18">
			<description>
				This version adds the AUDIT Module, includes Mediation Analysis, and contains improvements for other analyses.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.10.0" date="2019-06-11">
			<description>
				User Interface completely rewritten and many many other changes.
				See https://jasp-stats.org/blog/ for more info!
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.9.2" date="2018-12-10">
			<description>
				Computed columns stabilized and some extra stuff.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.9.1" date="2018-10-11">
			<description>
				New version of JASP with a first version of computed columns and many other things.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.9.0" date="2018-06-27">
			<description>
				New version of JASP with filtering, a partially rebuilt interface and many other things.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.8.6" date="2018-02-22">
			<description>
				First flatpak release
			</description>
		</release>
	</releases>
​</component>
