<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Copyright 2020 University of Amsterdam -->
<component type="desktop">
	<id>org.jaspstats.JASP</id>
	<launchable type="desktop-id">org.jaspstats.JASP.desktop</launchable>
	<name>JASP</name>
	<summary>Standard statistical analyses, both classical and Bayesian</summary>
	<metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
	<project_license>AGPL-3.0+</project_license>
	<content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
	<developer_name>University of Amsterdam</developer_name>
    <update_contact>joris@jorisgoosen.nl</update_contact>
	<description>
		<p>
			​JASP is a cross platform statistical software program with a state-of-the-art graphical user interface. 
			It offers standard analysis procedures in both	their classical and Bayesian form. 
		</p>
		<p>
			It was designed with the user in mind: APA-formatted tables can be copy-pasted in your word processor, output can be extensively annotated, adjustment of input options dynamically changes the output, and selecting 
			old output revives the associated input choices for inspection and adjustment.
		</p>
		<p>
			JASP is also statistically inclusive, as it offers both frequentist and Bayesian analysis methods. 
			Indeed, the primary motivation for JASP is to make it easier for statistical practitioners to conduct Bayesian analyses.
		</p>
	</description>
	<translation/>
	<screenshots>
		<screenshot type="default">
			<caption xml:lang="en-GB">Shows the dataviewer of JASP flanked with the options and output for the Independent Samples T-Test</caption>
			<image type="source" width="1600" height="900">https://raw.githubusercontent.com/jasp-stats/jasp-desktop/development/Tools/flatpak/JASP-screenshot-0.png</image>
		</screenshot>
	</screenshots>
	<url type="homepage">http://www.jasp-stats.org</url>
	<url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/jasp-stats/jasp-issues/issues</url>
	<url type="donation">https://jasp-stats.org/donate/</url>
	<releases>
	<release version="0.12" date="2020-20-04">
			<description>
				Updated R to 3.6.1 and rewrote (almost) all analyses to make use of new internal API (jaspResults).
				Added a dark theme and support for dutch language.
				Modules added: Bayesian meta-analysis, JAGS, Discover Distributions, Visual Modeling and Equivalence Testing.
				And much more, see our blog for more information!
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.11.1" date="2019-10-11">
			<description>
				This version fixes a bug with certain systems having trouble running certain analyses when the path contains non-latin characters.
				It also removes the inherit-gl-extension which causes some trouble for certain flatpak users.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.11.0" date="2019-09-24">
			<description>
				This version adds the Machine Learning Module, which adds a variety of classification, regression and clustering analyses.
				It also adds support for reading Stata and SAS files while updating the SPSS support through the use of ReadStat.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.10.2" date="2019-07-18">
			<description>
				This version adds the AUDIT Module, includes Mediation Analysis, and contains improvements for other analyses.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.10.0" date="2019-06-11">
			<description>
				User Interface completely rewritten and many many other changes.
				See https://jasp-stats.org/blog/ for more info!
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.9.2" date="2018-12-10">
			<description>
				Computed columns stabilized and some extra stuff.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.9.1" date="2018-10-11">
			<description>
				New version of JASP with a first version of computed columns and many other things.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.9.0" date="2018-06-27">
			<description>
				New version of JASP with filtering, a partially rebuilt interface and many other things.
			</description>
		</release>
		<release version="0.8.6" date="2018-02-22">
			<description>
				First flatpak release
			</description>
		</release>
	</releases>
​</component>
